■ gjmcgough@gmail.com▶ 6784910885♥ San Diego, CA

in gjmcgough O gjmcgough

SUMMARY

I am a full stack web developer with a passion for the the ocean, outdoors, athletics, and music. I come from a sailor background with 5 years experience working on various ocean going commercial vessels where attention to detail, ability to focus on the task at hand, teamwork, and leadership were crucial to successful voyages. I look forward to using my skills, knowledge, and creativity to enhance people's experiences in doing the things they love to do.

EDUCATION

Dev Bootcamp

Web Development 2016

Dev Bootcamp is a short-term, immersive program that transforms beginners into full-stack web developers. Dev Bootcamp focuses on Ruby, JavaScript, Ruby on Rails, common JavaScript libraries, SQL, HTML and CSS, as well as pair programming, and agile and test driven development. The program also integrates building team skills like communication, empathy, and effective feedback.

SUNY Maritime College

BS Marine Transposrtation 2011

SUNY Maritime's Marine Transportation Degree focuses on the Maritime industry, and obtaining a Coast Guard License to operate ocean going vessels.

SKILLS

TECHNICAL: Ruby, Javascript, Ruby on Rails, HTML, CSS, PostgreSQL, Active Record, Sinatra, jQuery, AngularJS, AWS S3

EXPERIENCE

LIZANO PHOTOGRAPHY

Developer

San Diego, CA Dec 2016 to Current

Lizano Photography (www.lizanophotography.com) is a custom photography portfolio app created for a local San Diego photographer. The idea behind this app is to allow the photographer to create galleries and upload photographs to display to the public. The minimal, sleek design of the app focuses the visitors attention on the vibrant images, and allows easy navigation throughout the site. The app also contains hidden admin functionality which gives the photographer full control over creating and deleting galleries, uploading and deleting images, and selecting gallery cover images. I built this app in Rails and Angular, while using AWS S3 to store the photographs. I also used gems such as Paperclip and ImageMagick for uploading the images and creating cropped and resized thumbnails. The app is in it's early stages and is constantly being improved.

LINK2 - SAN DIEGO REGIONAL EDC

Developer

San Diego, CA Jan 2017 to Current

Link2 is a Rails 5 web app we are developing for the San Diego Regional Economic Development Committee. The idea behind Link2 is to provide outgoing college students with information on local San Diego industries. SD EDC also hosts events throughout the year connecting students with employers. The Link2 app will use the Eventbrite API to display upcoming events in different San Diego industries.

KIRBY OFFSHORE MARINE

Chief Mate / Second Mate

Seattle, WA Jun 2012 to May 2016

Mate on various tug boats. Responsibilities include: Navigation and cargo watches; docking of the vessel; evaluate daily and emergency procedures aboard the vessel, and alter them if there is a safer, more efficient way to accomplish the task; create voyage plans and routes for trips; coordinate jobs with customers and work with docks to improve on safety and efficiency through our operations.

GREGORY MCGOUGH FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

PROJECTS

KARAOKE ROLLETTE

Karaoke Rollette is a twist on karaoke. The first feature allows users to quickly add songs to their playlist on the go, using Spotify's open endpoints to validate the songs the users are adding. The second feature is where the fun starts. Users can create/join parties where, a random user in the party will be matched up with a random song from any playlist of any user in the party. We built Karaoke Rollette as an 8 day final project at Dev Bootcamp. We used lonic, AngularJS, and Sass to build the native app, and Rails to build a custom API to store users data and leverage Spotify open end points to verify song data entered by the users.

PANTRIES

Pantries is a web app designed to let multiple users have access to a grocery list. The idea is that a user would be able to create a grocery list, or join one (with permission of the creator) and be able to add or remove items from the list. This way members of a single household, office, etc. would be able to see what items are already on the list, add items to the list, and shop for the items when the next person goes to the store. This app was created in Sinatra during a 2 day passion project at Dev Bootcamp, where I wanted to work on building an app with a more complex schema.

INVOLVEMENT

SD TECH/SURF MEETUP · Organizer San Diego

We are a group of tech professionals that meet every Saturday morning to surf!

JUST CALL US VOLUNTEERS · Volunteer San Diego

Prepare and serve meals to San Diego's homeless community.

AWARDS

SUNY School System · SUNY CHANCELLOR SCHOLAR ATHLETE

Chancellor of the SUNY school system picks and recognizes scholar athletes every year.

May 2011